A Guide to the Libertarian Party Papers, 1976-1983
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Libertarian Party Papers 1976-1983
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10187-n
This collection contains 122 items.
Roger Lea MacBride
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This material was given to the Library by Mr. Roger MacBride of Charlottesville, Virginia, on September 27, 1983.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of 122 items, 1976-1983, papers from the involvement of Roger Lea MacBride with the Libertarian Party. Included in the collection are correspondence, a 1983 report from the national party chairman, a paper regarding the libertarian-conservative tradition, a legal document, numerous state and national newsletters, convention and campaign pamphlets, newspaper clippings, photographs of MacBride, and memorabilia. The correspondence concerns party policies and internal factionalism between liberals and conservatives, particularly at the 1983 Libertarian convention. The memorabilia includes campaign and convention buttons, balloons, a belt buckle, a cup, a banner, and a t-shirt.
Contents List
- Correspondence 1979-1983, n.d., 23 items
- Report from Alicia Garcia Clark, National Chair and Executive Officer of the Libertarian Party (1981-1983) 1983, 1 item
- "The Libertarian-Conservative Tradition," by Dirk W. Leasure 1982, 1 item
- Roger L. MacBride v. Shirley Hassler judgement 1976 Sept., 1 item
- Colorado Liberty 1981 Aug., 1 item
- LP 10 Convention News1981 Aug., 2 items
- Free Texas 1979 Sept. - Dec., 2 items
- Frontlines 1979 July-1981 Jan., 4 items
- Individual Liberty 1980 Dec., 1 item
- New Hampshire Libertarian Lines 1979 June, Sept., 2 items
- LP News 1979 May-1983 June, 3 items
- Gary North's Remnant Review 1983 Feb., 1 item
- Update 1983 June, Sept., 2 items
- "Q & A about the Libertarian Party" n.d., 1 item
- Campaign pamphlets and banner n.d. 1980, 3 items
- Convention pamphlets 1979-1983, 7 items
- Dessert Recipes, MacBride picnic 1979, 1 item
- Newspaper clippings re RLM 1976-1983, 20 items
- Photographs of Roger MacBride 1976, n.d., 8 items
- Miscellaneous 1979, n.d., 3 items